<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on PHP Scaling</title>
    <link>https://www.phpscaling.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on PHP Scaling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2023, Alister Bulman; all rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 11:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.phpscaling.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recently....</title>
      <link>https://www.phpscaling.com/post/recently/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 11:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phpscaling.com/post/recently/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been one of those quiet spots around here for a while, so here&#39;s the catch-up on what has been happening while I was not posting.
I&#39;ve recently finished a short contract working with an agency, Transform (part of the Engine group) working with a couple of government departments. The Office Of The Public Guardian receives, checks and stores Lasting Powers of Attorney - a legal document that you write while still mentally compentant to say what you would like to happen should the worst occur, and by whom you want to do it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>svn checkouts vs exports for live versions</title>
      <link>https://www.phpscaling.com/post/svn-checkouts-vs-exports-for-live-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 19:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phpscaling.com/post/svn-checkouts-vs-exports-for-live-versions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve read http://www.svn-checkout.co.uk/2008/01/19/how-to-release-new-versions-of-websites/ via http://www.lornajane.net/posts/2008/SVN-Deployment-and-a-New-Site and while I consider revision control an essential tool (a few years ago, my job was the only one in the previous five years where I didn&#39;t have to install my own RCS), I somewhat disagree on the idea they suggest.
That first link, &#39;how to release new versions of websites&#39;, suggests checking out a version of the site as a working copy, (it&#39;s certainly something I&#39;ve done before now), but then it goes on to use the &#39;svn switch&#39; capability to move between versions (of course, they are also doing in in TortoiseSvn, and there for the live web-server is likely to be running Windows, no way I&#39;d run a server on Windows - not even for testing).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
