<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>funemployment on PHP Scaling</title>
    <link>https://phpscaling.com/tags/funemployment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in funemployment on PHP Scaling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2023, Alister Bulman; all rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 11:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phpscaling.com/tags/funemployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recently....</title>
      <link>https://phpscaling.com/post/recently/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 11:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/recently/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It&#39;s been one of those quiet spots around here for a while, so here&#39;s the catch-up on what has been happening while I was not posting.
I&#39;ve recently finished a short contract working with an agency, Transform (part of the Engine group) working with a couple of government departments. The Office Of The Public Guardian receives, checks and stores Lasting Powers of Attorney - a legal document that you write while still mentally compentant to say what you would like to happen should the worst occur, and by whom you want to do it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from the coalface</title>
      <link>https://phpscaling.com/post/back-from-the-coalface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 11:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/back-from-the-coalface/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been pretty busy in the last couple of years, first at Binweevils and in 2011, PeerIndex - hence the utter lack of posts, but as the note on my personal CV site says, I&#39;m taking some time off between looking for my next role. This does give the opportunity to write more of PHP Scaling and the tools around development that I&#39;ve been using in the last couple of years, and that have been piquing my curiosity.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>($me instanceOf ZCE) === true</title>
      <link>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Phew. That would have been embarrassing if I&#39;d not passed my ZCE on Thursday afternoon (Jun 4th, 2009).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
