<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zce on PHP Scaling</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/series/zce/</link><description>Recent content in zce on PHP Scaling</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2023, Alister Bulman; all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 11:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phpscaling.com/series/zce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>($me instanceOf ZCE) === true</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</guid><description>
Phew. That would have been embarrassing if I'd not passed my ZCE on Thursday afternoon (Jun 4th, 2009).</description></item><item><title>I laugh at your ZCE exam prep tests #2</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/i-laugh-at-your-zce-exam-prep-tests-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 14:20:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/i-laugh-at-your-zce-exam-prep-tests-2/</guid><description>
Back at the PHP London Conference at the end of February, iBuildings was offering a little test, with prize for people that could do well answering the sort of questions that are on the ZCE exam. Never one to turn down something useful for free, I took ten minutes to answer the eight questions. A few weeks later, I get an email from them/Zend to say I'd won the chance to take an exam – ZCE, or ZFE (Zend Framework).</description></item><item><title>ZCE prep - practice test #1</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/zce-prep-practice-test-1-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/zce-prep-practice-test-1-2/</guid><description>
Well, I've just completed the PHP Arch 'Vulcan' practice test – the first of up to five such practice tests I've purchased. I have quite deliberately not gone through what study materials I have on hand before I took this test (I wanted to get a baseline), but none the less got an 'EXCELLENT' final score, and the same 'Excellent' on seven of the twelve sections the pre-test is broken down into.</description></item><item><title>ZCE prep - and dumb tests</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/zce-prep-and-dumb-tests-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/zce-prep-and-dumb-tests-2/</guid><description>
This week I'm going to take the first of my PHPArch.com's ZCE prep test – then I'll read the book and see they they expect me to know.
Going for the Zend Certification is something I've been thinking of doing for a couple of years, and especially now that it covers PHP5 – and increasingly good practices and security topics. It's not that I need to get the ZCE, I'd go for it , for the intellectual challenge if nothing else.</description></item></channel></rss>