<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quick on PHP Scaling</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/tags/quick/</link><description>Recent content in quick on PHP Scaling</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2023, Alister Bulman; all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 17:32:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phpscaling.com/tags/quick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hire quickly: Addendum, recruiters</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/hire-quickly-addendum-recruiters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 17:32:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/hire-quickly-addendum-recruiters/</guid><description>
Recruiters: Here's the rules.
The first recruiter to tell me the company name, and then send the job-spec gets to forward my details - if I think it's interesting. No company name, or spec, no chance If you send my details without my OK, you lose. And I tell the company you are a loser (chances are, they are too). Sending me all the information I could want to know is good - but when you do it on spec (and probably en-mass as well), does not mean that you get to claim the bounty.</description></item><item><title>Jailbreaking your Kindle, and putting new 'screensaver' images</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/jailbreaking-your-kindle-and-putting-new-screensaver-images/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 15:16:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/jailbreaking-your-kindle-and-putting-new-screensaver-images/</guid><description>
A quick fun post for those of you with an Amazon Kindle - some instructions on how to a) jailbreak your reader (trivially easy), and then b) put your own wallpapers on there, so you get a more interesting 'screensaver'.
It's really easy, no more than 20 mins and a couple of reboots/software updates. Most of the time is literally waiting for the reader to restart after you've placed a file in the base directory.</description></item><item><title>Booze at tech meetups</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/booze-at-meetups/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 17:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/booze-at-meetups/</guid><description>
I was out last night at the The Big Xmas [bash] #, near Silicon Roundabout. It was a fun night out meeting various people, tech, business and recruiters. Oh, the shame though - I was wearing the same T-shirt as someone else - and, yes, I have indeed replaced people with small shell scripts.
Now, to the main part of what this post is about - the rant. It's not aimed at the particular event last night alone though.</description></item><item><title>Back from the coalface</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/back-from-the-coalface/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 11:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/back-from-the-coalface/</guid><description>
I've been pretty busy in the last couple of years, first at Binweevils and in 2011, PeerIndex - hence the utter lack of posts, but as the note on my personal CV site says, I'm taking some time off between looking for my next role. This does give the opportunity to write more of PHP Scaling and the tools around development that I've been using in the last couple of years, and that have been piquing my curiosity.</description></item><item><title>($me instanceOf ZCE) === true</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/me-instanceof-zce-true/</guid><description>
Phew. That would have been embarrassing if I'd not passed my ZCE on Thursday afternoon (Jun 4th, 2009).</description></item><item><title>Upcoming posts - keep watching</title><link>https://phpscaling.com/post/upcoming-posts-keep-watching/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 10:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phpscaling.com/post/upcoming-posts-keep-watching/</guid><description>
Just a quick note on what is going to be posted in the next few weeks – I've got a few significant pieces in mind for various topics – including:
Doing the work elsewhere – asynchronous queues This is going to be a series of articles – and to support it, I'm rewriting some code that I had originally wrote for my last job (v2, and so significantly improved over the original).</description></item></channel></rss>